Guide to the Lionel Stevenson Papers, 1808-1989, bulk 1911-1974 UA.29.02.0014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lionel Stevenson papers
1808-1989, bulk 1911-1974
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stevenson, Lionel, 1902-1973
UA.29.02.0014
25.25 Linear Feet
Lionel Stevenson was James B. Duke Professor of English at Duke University from 1955-1971. This collection contains artwork, canadiana, clippings, correspondence, course material, diaries, financial records, manuscripts, photographs, and scrapbooks regarding the life and work of Lionel Stevenson. The material ranges in date from 1808-1989, bulk from 1911-1974.
30,300 items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Lionel Stevenson Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1974-2001.
Biographical Note
Lionel Stevenson was born in Edinburgh, Scotland, on July 16, 1902. He moved to British Columbia in September, 1907, and finally to America in August, 1923. Stevenson became naturalized as an American citizen on May 23, 1930. He had a wife, Lillian, and one step daughter, Marietta.
Stevenson received his B.A. from the University of British Columbia in 1922, M.A. from the University of Toronto in 1923, his Ph.D. from the University of California in 1925, and his B. Litt., from the University of Oxford in 1935.
He was James B. Duke Professor of English at Duke University from 1955-1970. Before coming to Duke, Stevenson held teaching positions at the University of California, 1925-1930, Arizona State College, 1930-1937, and the University of Southern California, 1937-1955. He also was a Visiting Professor at the University of Illinois, 1952-1953, and Visiting Lecturer at University of Oxford, 1960-1961.
Stevenson held positions as Vice-president of the Western College Association, 1946-1947, Chairman of the Southern Humanities Conference, 1959-1960, and John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Fellow, 1960-1961.
Lionel Stevenson died on December 21, 1973, at the age of 71.
Collection Overview
The papers of Lionel Stevenson span the years 1808 to 1989, although the bulk of the material dates from the 1920s to 1973. They consist of canadiana; clippings; correspondence; course material; general files; manuscripts and notes; notes, papers, and research; non-textual material; organizations; oversized materials; and writings. The collection documents Lionel Stevenson's work as both an author and a professor, as well as an avid collector of news clippings and expert on the Cary family. Subject areas include genealogy of the Cary family, Canadian authors and poets, and photographs, and nineteenth century English literary criticism.
The General Files series is mainly comprised of personal files, like financial records and general miscellany. The Non-Textual Material series contains over 230 cartes de visite photographs, chiefly of the Cary family, as well as other various photographs and pictures. The bulk of the Writings series contains mainly articles and drafts. Notable in this series is Stevenson's Masters thesis. The series Course Material contains folders of syllabi, lecture notes, and miscellaneous papers relating to courses he taught. The Notes, Papers, and Research series contains research notes relating to the writings of Lionel Stevenson. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Notable in this series are letters from literary figures Joyce Cary, Bliss Carman, and Evelyn Waugh. The Organizations contains papers regarding the various groups Stevenson belonged to, notably the Canadian Authors Association, Dickens Fellowship, Modern Language Association, and the PEN Congress. The Manuscript and Notes series contains miscellaneous papers and a manuscript of Revolt Among the Artists. The bulk of the Clippings series are clippings removed from Correspondence and arranged alphabetically. The Diaries series is two boxes filled with Stevenon's personal diaries kept from 1919 to 1974. The Oversized Material series contains clippings and papers removed from their respective series, as well as three scrapbooks of clippings, a novel, audio cassette, and a poster for an essay contest. Canadiana contains miscellaneous Canadian memorabilia that Stevenson collected. The last series Oversized Artwork contains paintings and pictures that were formerly housed in the general oversized collection.
Clippings (information artifacts); Canadiana; English literature -- 19th century; Poets, Canadian; Authors, Canadian; Duke University. Department of English; Carman, Bliss; Stevenson, Lionel, 1902-1973; Cary, Joyce
- General Files, 1 box
  - 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - 32nd and 34th Poets Dinner flyers (Box 1)
  - 88 Fairacres Road, Oxford (Box 1)
  - Address Lists (Box 1)
  - Automobile, 1955- (Box 1)
  - British Automobile, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Crank Letters (Box 1)
  - Duke University Library: Books Ordered (Box 1)
  - Duke University Calendar, Feb. 23-Mar. 2, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Financial Records Sept. 15, 1937-Dec. 31, 1941; Jan. 1, 1946-Aug. 31, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Financial Records, Jan. 1, 1942-Dec. 31, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Fiancial Records Sept. 1, 1948-Dec. 31, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Financial Records Jan. 1, 1953-Dec. 31, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Alumni (Box 1)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Honor Roll Certificates, Public School, B.C., 1912-1914 (Box 1)
  - Income Tax Data (Box 1)
  - Invitations (Box 1)
  - Lecture Flyer, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Lionel Stevenson Biographical Information (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Lionel Stevenson Biographical Information (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Library Dedication Committee (Box 1)
  - Loose Materials (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Loose Materials (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Loose Materials (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Mabel Rose Stevenson (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Books Brochures (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Books Brochures (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Menus, Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Brochures (Box 1)
  - Oxford High School for Girls (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and Programs (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and Programs Re: Lionel Stevenson and the University of Southern California (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures Re: Canadian Literature and Authors (Box 1)
  - Papers Re: Autograph Collectiong, 1938-1971 (Box 1)
  - Party Guest Lists (Box 1)
  - Portraits Shipped to Joyce Cary (Box 1)
  - Programs Featuring Lionel Stevenson (Box 1)
  - Radcliffe College (Box 1)
  - Removal: Los Angeles to Durham (Box 1)
  - Reviews of The Pre-Raphaelite Poets (Box 1)
  - Summer, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Summer, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Summer, 1965 (Box 1)
  - University of British Columbia Graduation Programs, 1919-1923 (Box 1)
  - University Donation Requests (Box 1)
  - The University of Chicago Press Book, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled Folder (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled Folder (2 of 2) (Box 1)
- Non-Textual Material, .5 boxes
  - Cartes de Visite (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Cartes de Visite (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Cartes de Visite (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Photographs - Joyce Cary (Box 2)
  - Photographs - Cary Family (Box 2)
  - Photographs - P. Trudeau Visit, 1974, Exhibit and Snapshots (Box 2)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Pictures - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Pictures and Clippings of Authors (Box 2)
- Writings, 1.5 boxes
  - Canadian Books - Fall-Winter List, ca. 1929 (Box 2)
  - Carlyle and Meredith (Box 2)
  - Huntington Library, Lever Letters (Box 2)
  - Journal (Box 2)
  - Linguistic History - English 22 (Box 2)
  - Notes, Papers and Outlines Re: Victorian Period (Box 2)
  - Notes on George du Maurier (Box 2)
  - Notes on Lever (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets by Linonel Stevenson (Box 2)
  - Plays (Box 2)
  - Poems by Friends (Box 2)
  - Prelude of 1799 (Box 2)
  - Unfinished and Inferior Poems (Box 2)
  - Untitled Manuscript (1 of 4) (Box 2)
  - Untitled Manuscript (2 of 4) (Box 2)
  - Untitled Manuscript (3 of 4) (Box 2)
  - Untitled Manuscript (4 of 4) (Box 2)
  - Verse by Lionel Stevenson (Box 2)
  - Works by Other Authors (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - Works by Other Authors (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - "1859" Article (Box 3)
  - American Literature Articles (Box 3)
  - An Approach to the Study of History (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - An Approach to the Study of History (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Arnold Article (Box 3)
  - Articles on Education (Box 3)
  - Articles on Research Methods (Box 3)
  - Book Reviews - Academic Periodicals (Box 3)
  - Browning Article (Box 3)
  - The Cary Family of Inishowen (Box 3)
  - Canadian Literature Articles (Box 3)
  - Coleridge Article (Box 3)
  - Contemporary Literature Articles (Box 3)
  - The Crash of Old 314 or Kommafolty (Box 3)
  - Dickens Article (Box 3)
  - The Dramatic Monologue Employed by Robert Browning, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Du Maurier Article (Box 3)
  - The Facultiad (Box 3)
  - Four Poetry Tours (Radio Addresses) (Box 3)
  - Galsworthy Article (Box 3)
  - "Irresponsible Decade" Article (Box 3)
  - John Millington Synge, by Lionel Stevenson (Box 3)
  - Juvenilia - Lionel Stevenson (Box 3)
  - Los Angeles Daily News Book Reviews (Box 3)
  - Masters Thesis, 1923 (Box 3)
  - Meredith Articles (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (1 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (2 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (3 of 3) (Box 3)
  - The Novel - Articles (Box 3)
  - Plays (Box 3)
  - Poems (Box 3)
  - Poetry - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 3)
  - Published Articles and Reviews, 1960 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Publishd Articles and Reviews, 1960 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Radio Address on Canadian Literature (Box 3)
  - Television Lecture - How a Biogrpahy is Written (Box 3)
  - Tennyson Articles (Box 3)
  - Thackeray Articles (Box 3)
  - Trollope Articles (Box 3)
  - Uncollected Poems (Box 3)
  - Unpublished Mss (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (1 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (2 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (3 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (4 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (5 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (6 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (7 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Untilted Manuscript (8 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Victorian Poetry Articles (Box 3)
- Course Material, .5 boxes
  - Duke University - Ph.D. Exams, 1956-1972 (Box 4)
  - English 341: Studies in English Romanticism (Box 4)
  - English 349 cd, 350 cd (Box 4)
  - English 351-352, Reports (Box 4)
  - English 341 (Box 4)
  - English 192, 398-399 (Box 4)
  - English 125-126, Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English (221) 241 (Box 4)
  - English 222 (Box 4)
  - English (223) 245 (Box 4)
  - English (224) 246 (Box 4)
  - English 262 (Box 4)
  - English 290: Cross Currents in English-French-American Cultures (Box 4)
  - English 55-56: Representative Writers, Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English 351-352: Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - English 381-382: 19th Century Seminar (Box 4)
  - English 128 (Box 4)
  - English 131-131, Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English 245-246: Later 19th Century Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English 333: Literature of Victorian Age, University of Houston, Fall 1972 (Box 4)
  - English 334: Literature of Victorian Age, University of Houston, Spring 1973 (Box 4)
  - English 347, Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English 348, Permanent Materials (Box 4)
  - English 638: Brittish Fiction, 1890-1954, University of Houston, Spring 1973 (Box 4)
  - English 665: The English Novel, University of Houston, Fall 1972 (Box 4)
  - Humanities Seminar, 1969 (Box 4)
  - NYU 0266: Intellectual Backgrounds, 1800-1900 (Box 4)
  - NYU G-2662-2663: The Victorian Novel, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - USC English 345: The Novel in English Since 1860, Summer 1958 (Box 4)
  - USC English 581: Seminar in the Novel and Short Story, Summer 1958 (Box 4)
- Notes, Papers and Research, .5 boxes
  - List of Papers Reviewed (Box 4)
  - Lady Morgan (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (1 of 5) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (2 of 5) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (3 of 5) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (4 of 5) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (5 of 5) (Box 4)
  - Note Cards (Box 4)
  - Research Projects (Box 4)
  - Re: William Makepeace Thackeray (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Re: William Makepeace Thackeray (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray, July 18, 1811-July, 1830 (Box 4)
  - Willliam Makepeace Thackeray, July, 1830-July, 1840 (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray, July, 1840-July, 1848 (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray, July, 1848-July, 1855 (Box 4)
  - William Makepeace Thackeray, July, 1855-Dec. 24, 1863 (Box 4)
  - Transcribed Letters Re: Charles Lever (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Transcribed Letters Re: Charles Lever (2 of 2) (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 3.5 boxes
  - A (Box 5)
  - Ba-Birney (Box 5)
  - Bop-Carm (Box 5)
  - Carn-Cary (Box 5)
  - Cary-Cn (Box 5)
  - Co-Dal (Box 5)
  - Dam-Dz (Box 5)
  - Ea-Ell (Box 5)
  - Elm-F (Box 5)
  - G-Hi (Box 5)
  - Ho-Kei (Box 5)
  - Kej-Kh (Box 5)
  - Ki-Lb (Box 5)
  - Lc-Lo (Box 5)
  - Lp-Male (Box 5)
  - Macf-Man (Box 5)
  - Mao-Mark (Box 6)
  - Marl-Mig (Box 6)
  - Mih-Mz (Box 6)
  - N-O (Box 6)
  - Pa-Pra (Box 6)
  - Prb-Robe (Box 6)
  - Robf-Sed (Box 6)
  - See-Smyth (Box 6)
  - Smythe (Box 6)
  - Sn-Sz (Box 6)
  - T-Wa (Box 6)
  - Wb-Wi (Box 6)
  - Wj-Z (Box 6)
  - Anthologies (Box 6)
  - Appraisals of Canadian Literature (Box 6)
  - Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (Box 6)
  - Campus World Inc, The English Novel (Box 6)
  - Collier's Encyclopedia (Box 6)
  - Contemporary Literary Scholarship (Box 6)
  - Darwin Among the Poets (Box 6)
  - Darwin Among the Poets Distribution of Final Copies (Box 6)
  - Dr. Quicksilver (Box 6)
  - The Egoist Introduction (Box 6)
  - Encyclopedia Americana: Articles on Meredith, Chronicles, Trollope, Thackeray, Etc. (Box 6)
  - The English Novel: A Panorama (Box 6)
  - The English Novel Constable and Company (Box 6)
  - Esther Waters Introduction (Box 7)
  - Galsworthy The Man of Property Introduction (Box 7)
  - Handbook of the Victorian Period (Box 7)
  - History of the English Novel XI (Box 7)
  - The Image and the Work (Box 7)
  - Journal of 19th Century Fiction (Box 7)
  - Magazines (Prose) (1 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Magazines (Prose) (2 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Magazines (Poetry) (Box 7)
  - Meredith The Ordeal of Richard Feverel Introduction (Box 7)
  - Meredith and the Problem of Style in the Novel (Box 7)
  - 19th Century English Prose (Box 7)
  - Novels of Charles Lever - Introduction (Box 7)
  - The Ordeal of George Meredith Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 7)
  - The Ordeal of George Meredith Curtis Brown, Ltd. (Box 7)
  - The Ordeal of George Meredith Financial Record (Box 7)
  - The Ordeal of George Meredith Letters from Readers (Box 7)
  - Pacific Spectator (Box 7)
  - Personalist (Box 7)
  - Publishers - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Scribner's - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 7)
  - College English (Box 7)
  - Showman of Vanity Fair Financial Record (Box 7)
  - Showman of Vanity Fair Letters from Readers (Box 7)
  - Showman of Vanity FairS. J. R. Saunders and Company (Box 7)
  - Showman of Vanity Fair Curtis Brown Ltd., Chapman and Hall (Box 7)
  - Showman of Vanity Fair A and S Lyons, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 7)
  - South Atlantic Quarterly (Box 7)
  - Studies in English Literature (Box 7)
  - A Thackeray Library Introduction (Box 7)
  - Thackeray Henry Esmond Introduction (Harper) (Box 7)
  - Thackeray Henry Esmond Introduction (Bantam) (Box 7)
  - Vanity Fair Introduction, Pocket Books (Box 7)
  - Victorian Literature: Modern Essays in Criticism (Box 7)
  - Victorian Poetry and Criticism (Box 7)
  - Victorian Poets: A Review of Research (Box 7)
  - Victorian Studies (Box 7)
  - Wild Irish Girl (Box 7)
  - World Book Encyclopedia (Box 7)
  - Ph.D. Candidates
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Applewhite, James W. (Box 7)
    - Armitage, Christopher (Box 7)
    - Belflower, James Robert (Box 7)
    - Bell, Vereen M. (Box 7)
    - Bishop, Charles (Box 7)
    - Blake, Robert G. (Box 7)
    - Chard, Leslie Frank (Box 7)
    - Cole, Frances A. (Box 7)
    - Cunningham, John M. (Box 7)
    - De Graaff, Robert M. (Box 7)
    - Dunn, John J. (Box 7)
    - Edge, Charles (Box 7)
    - Felgar, Robert P. (Box 7)
    - Grimes, Terrence L. (Box 7)
    - Gross, James R. (Box 7)
    - Halloran, William F. (Box 7)
    - Harries, W. Styron (Box 7)
    - James, Norman (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Charles (Box 7)
    - Jordan, Frank Jr. (Box 7)
    - Kauvar, Gerald B. (Box 7)
    - Kelly, Richard M. (Box 7)
    - Kirby Smith, Virginia (Box 7)
    - Kirk Patrick, Larry James (Box 7)
    - Lincecum, Jerry Bryan (Box 7)
    - Locke, Elizabeth (Box 8)
    - Lohman, William J. (Box 8)
    - McCelvey, George E. (Box 8)
    - McIlwaine, Robert S. (Box 8)
    - Miller, Arthur Mc. A. (Box 8)
    - Miller, Mary Ruth (Box 8)
    - Richman, Larry K. (Box 8)
    - Rosenwald, John R. (Box 8)
    - Schneider, Joseph L. (Box 8)
    - Schueler, Robert A. (Box 8)
    - Smith, Carolyn Herbert (Box 8)
    - Sutton, Max (Box 8)
    - Tuitt, Ralph M. (Box 8)
    - Zimmerman, Robert L. (Box 8)
  - Lecture Engagements (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1935-1973 (Box 8)
  - Positions (Box 8)
- Organizations, 3 boxes
  - Academy of Literary Studies (Box 8)
  - American College Bureau (Box 8)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 8)
  - American Library Association (Box 8)
  - Arizona State College, Tempe (Box 8)
  - Arts and Letters Club, Toronto (Box 8)
  - Authors' Club (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Authors' Club (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Authors' Club, London (Box 8)
  - Bodleian Library, Oxford University (Box 8)
  - Books in Review Program (Box 8)
  - British Commonwealth Literature Conference (MLA) (Box 8)
  - Californial Federation of Chaparral Poets (Box 8)
  - California Poets, Correspondence (Box 8)
  - California Writers' Club (Box 8)
  - California Writers' Club Monthly Letter, Oct. 1924-Sept. 1930 (Box 8)
  - California Writers' Guild (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association (1 of 3) (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association (2 of 3) (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association (3 of 3) (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association, Vancouver Branch (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Vancouver, 1926 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Ottowa, 1927 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Montreal, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Toronto, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Vancouver, 1936 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Stannes, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Vancouver, 1941 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Ottowa, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Toronto, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Banff, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Halifax, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Ottowa, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Authors' Association Convention, Halifax, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Humanities Research Council (Box 8)
  - CEA Institute, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Chaparral Poets, Hollywood Chapter (Box 8)
  - Chaparral Poets, Los Angeles Chapter (Box 8)
  - Chaparral Poets, Other Chapters (Box 8)
  - College English Association (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - College English Association (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - College Language Association (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth Club Literature Medal Awards (Box 8)
  - Conference on Nineteenth Century Studies, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Declaration of In TER dependence (Box 8)
  - Dickens Fellowship, East Bay Branch (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship, Headquarters (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship, Los Angeles Branch (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship, Los Angeles Branch: Enrollment Certificate, October 27, 1937 (Box 18)
  - Dickens Fellowship, Other Branches (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship (1 of 4) (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship (2 of 4) (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship (3 of 4) (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship (4 of 4) (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship Photos and Clippings (Box 9)
  - Dickens Fellowship Conference - Edinburgh, 1929 (Box 9)
  - English Speaking Union (1 of 4) (Box 9)
  - English Speaking Union (2 of 4) (Box 9)
  - English Speaking Union (3 of 4) (Box 9)
  - English Speaking Union (4 of 4) (Box 9)
  - English-Speaking Union, Washington, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Faculty Club, University of Southern California (Box 9)
  - Fulbright Fellowships (Box 9)
  - Guggenheim Fellowships (Box 9)
  - Ina Coolbrith Circle (Box 9)
  - International Association of Professors of English (Box 9)
  - International Federation for Modern Languages and Literatures (Box 9)
  - International Federation for Modern Languages and Literatures, 1960 (Box 9)
  - International Federation for Modern Languages and Literatures, VII Congress (Box 9)
  - International Federation for Modern Languages and Literatures, IX Congress, New York, 1963 (Box 9)
  - John O'London Literary Circle (Box 9)
  - League of Western Writers (Box 9)
  - Lecture Engagements, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Mark Twain Society (Box 9)
  - Meet the Author Broadcast (Box 9)
  - Modern Humanities Research Association (1 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Modern Humanities Research Association (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - MLA Program, Dec. 1972 (Box 9)
  - Modern Language Association of America (1 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Modern Language Association of America (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Modern Language Association, English X Program, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Modern Language Association - Victorian Literature Group (Box 9)
  - National Council of Teachers of English (Box 9)
  - National Trust for Scotland (Box 9)
  - North Carolina Writers Conference (Box 9)
  - Oxford Preservation Trust (Box 10)
  - Oxford Society (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Oxford Society (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - PEN Club - Congresses (Box 10)
  - PEN Club, London (Box 10)
  - PEN Club, Los Angeles (Box 10)
  - PEN Club, San Fran (Box 10)
  - PEN Congresses Miscellaneous (1 of 4) (Box 10)
  - PEN Congresses Miscellaneous (2 of 4) (Box 10)
  - PEN Congresses Miscellaneous (3 of 4) (Box 10)
  - PEN Congresses Miscellaneous (4 of 4) (Box 10)
  - PEN Newsletters (Box 10)
  - PEN Congress - Endinburgh, 1934, Programs and Press Clippings (Box 10)
  - PEN Congress - Vienna, 1939 (Box 10)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 10)
  - Philological Association of the Pacific Coast (Box 10)
  - PMLA (Box 10)
  - Poet Laureatship of California (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards ( 1 of 3) (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards (2 of 3) (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards (3 of 3) (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards, 1951-1953 (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards, 1953-1959 (Box 10)
  - Poetry Awards Poems, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Poetry - Humorous Canadian Poetry (Box 10)
  - Poetry Society of America (Box 10)
  - Research Articles - Correspondence (Box 10)
  - Research Projects - Correspondence (Box 10)
  - Royal Society of Arts (Box 10)
  - Royal Society of Literature (Box 10)
  - Ryerson Press: Poetry Chapbooks (Box 10)
  - South Atlantic Modern Language Association (Box 10)
  - Southern Humanities Conference (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Southern Humanities Conference (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - St. Catherine's Association (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - St. Catherine's Association (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - St. Stephen's Church (Box 10)
  - University of British Columbia Alumni Association (Box 11)
  - University of British Columbia Southern California Branch (Box 11)
  - University Presses (Consultation) (1 of 3) (Box 11)
  - University Presses (Consultation) (2 of 3) (Box 11)
  - University Presses (Consultation) (3 of 3) (Box 11)
  - Vancouver Poetry Society, 1940-1968 (Box 11)
  - Western College Association (Box 11)
  - Writers' Roundtable, Hollywood (Box 11)
  - Tau Gamma Chapter of Sigma Tau Delta (Box 11)